Ernst Bacon Papers
Ernst Bacon Papers
- Manuscripts, musical
  - General music scores
    - Choral
      - General choral numbers, folio (Oversize 8)
        "A Carol" (original), 4 pages
        "Where Go the Boats" (original), 2 pages
        "Rain After the Drought" (original), 3 pages
        "Precepts Of Angelus Silesius" (1624-1677) (original), 11 pages
        "The Robe" (original), 2 pages
        "Shoutin' Pilgrim" (original), 3 pages
        "Morn and Night" (original), 1 page
        "Child's Evening Hymn" (original), 1 page
        "The Soule" (original), 1 page
        "Jonah" (original), 3 pages
        "Golden Rules" ( original), 2 pages
        "How Many?" (original), 2 pages
        "The Last Train" (original), 3 pages
        "Jonah" (original), 2 pages
        "The Long Farewell" (original), 2 pages
        "The Eternal Goodness" (original), 1 page
        "Freedom" (original), 2 pages
        "The Schoolboy" (original), 3 pages
        "Shouting Pilgrim" (original), 4 pages
        "Return of Spring" (original), 2 pages
        "Chop-Cherry" (original), 2 pages
        "Yes, I Do!" (original), 2 pages
        "Ode" (original), 4 pages
        "Love Somebody" (original), 2 pages
        "A Christmas Carol" (original), 1 page
        "Waiting" (original), 1 page
        "The Gambling Man" (original), 4 pages
        "Love Somebody" (original), 4 pages
        "The Pelican" (original), 2 pages
        "The Little Children" (original), 1 page
        "Money" (original), 2 pages
        "God" (original), 1 page
        "John Hardy" (original), 3 pages
        "Ode to Freedom" (original), 3 pages
        "Golden Rules" (original), 1 page
        "The Soldier's Little Boy" (original), 2 pages
        "John Hardy" (original), 7 pages
        "The Colorado Trail" (original), 3 pages
        "Shouting Pilgrim" (original), 7 pages
        "Freedom" (original), 1 page
        "Jonah" (original), 1 page
        "The Houn' Dawg" (original), 2 pages
        "Just Down Yonder" (original), 2 pages
        "The Camel" (original), 3 pages
        "Devilish Mary" (original), 4 pages
        "Schools and Rules""(original), 1 page
        "Precepts of Angelus Silesius" (original), 7 pages
        "Gifts from the Devil" (original), 2 pages
        "The Happier Sheep" (original), 2 pages
        "Down Yonder" (original), 4 pages
        "Gideon's Sword" (original), 1 page
    - Contrapuntal studies
      - Miscellaneous, early (Oversize 8)
        "Fugue" (reproduction), 5 pages
        "Fugue" (original), 4 pages
        "Prelude" (original), 3 pages
        "Fugal Fantasy" (original), 6 pages
        "Fugue for Two Pianos" (original), 20 pages
    - Opera
      - The Tempest, 1st version, folio (Oversize 8)
        "Storm Before Act. I, Sc. I" (original), 8 pages
        "While You Here Do Snoring Lie" Act I, Sc. II (original), 1 page
        Musical Fragments for "Tempest," Act I, Sc. II (original), 2 pages
        Fragments for The Tempest Act I, Sc. II (original), 2 pages
        "Enter Trinculo with a Burden of Wood" Act II, Sc.II (original), 2 pages
        "Log-Bearing Music" (original) Act III, Sc. I, 3 pages
        "Caliban, "That's Not the Tune" Act III, Sc. II (original), 2 pages
        "Ariel, "Is Nothing But Heart's Sorrow and a Clear Life Ensuing" (original), 1 page
        "Introduction to Act IV" (original), 3 pages
        "Prospero and Ariel Setting on Diverse Spirits" Act IV, Sc.I (original), 3 pages
        "Music of the Shapes" (original), 2 pages
        "No More Dams" (original), 2 pages
        "Stephano's Song" (original), 2 pages
        "Full Fathom Five" (original), 1 page
        "Marriage Blessing" (original), 2 pages
        "Music of the Goddesses" (original), 2 pages
    - Orchestral
      - Titled scores
        - Blue Ontario, includes miscellaneous scores; original; 63 pages (Oversize 8)
        - Country Roads, with lyrics; original; 31 pages (Oversize 8)
        - From These States, with lyrics; original; 87 pages (Oversize 3)
        - The Muffin Man, reproduction; spiral bound; 28 pages, 2 copies (Oversize 8)
        - The Muffin Man, reproduction; folio; 28 pages (Oversize 12)
      - Miscellaneous scores (Oversize 9)
        Prelude and Fugue (original), 26 pages
        Riolama (original), 21 pages
        Songs with Orchestra Bound (with lyrics) (original), 76 pages
        Symphony I 1st Movement (original), 68 pages
        Symphony I 3rd Movement (original), 38 pages
        "Never to Know" et al. (some with lyrics) (original), 131 pages
        "Tis Far Off Like a ( )" (some with lyrics) (original), 31 pages
    - Piano
      - Titled scores (Oversize 9)
        Burr Frolic Two Pianos (original), 11 pages
        The Coal-Shuttle Blues 1 Piano (original), 12 pages with 4 pages of revisions
        Riolama (original), 9 pages
        Symphony I 2 Piano Version (original), 90 pages
      - Titled scores (cont.) (Oversize 10)
        Symphony II 2 Piano Version (original), 26 pages
      - General piano scores, volume I, 1 volume (Oversize 12)
        "Grey Days" (reproduction), 1 page
        "Falling Snow" (reproduction), 5 pages
        "Those Damned Foreigners" (reproduction), 2 pages
        "Delirium of the City" (reproduction), 3 pages
        "The Prairies" (reproduction), 1 page
        "Boisterous Fugue" (reproduction), 8 pages
        "Rain Dripping Off the Roof" (reproduction), 1 page
        "Organ Grinder with Monkey" (rep;), 1 page
        "Gazing Out the Window" (reproduction), 1 page
        "Sweet Tones" (reproduction), 1 page
        "My Friends" (reproduction), 1 page
        "Goodbye to the Princess" (reproduction), 1 page
        "Fuge" (reproduction), 5 pages
        "Canonische Fuge" (reproduction), 4 pages
        "Fuge (drei stimmig)" (reproduction), 3 pages
        "Jazzing Shadows (Blues)" (reproduction), 8 pages
        "The Coal Shuttle Blues" (printed), 8 pages
      - General piano scores, volume II, 1 volume (Oversize 12)
        "Kankankee River" (printed) pub. by Wesley Webster, San Bruno, Cal., 11 pages
        "To the Children" (original), 2 pages
        "Organ Grinder with Monkey" (original), 3 pages
        "Tender Hands" (original), 2 pages
        "Sleepy River" (original), 3 pages
        "In Hungary" (original), 1 page
        "Gone Forever" (original), 1 page
        "Poc Hiss Piv Lento" (original), 1 page
        Miscellaneous Practice Pages (original), 2 pages
        "Wastin' Time" (original), 6 pages
        "Trio" (original), 6 pages
        "Coda" (original), 2 pages
        "Appendix" (original), 2 pages
        "How Still the Bells" (original), 3 pages
    - Sketch books
      - [Untitled] (Box 4)
        "Canons and Rounds" (original), 29 pages
        "Cello, Sonata, Orchestra" (original), 74 pages
        "The Cockleburr Frolic" (original), 109 pages
        "Elk Lake" (original), 61 pages
        "Epigrams" (original), 42 pages
        "Further Sketches for 'Drumlin Garden'" (original), 59 pages
        "John Hardy" et al. (original), 60 pages
        "A Little Cycle of Christmas Carols for Cello & Piano" (orig.), 73 pages
        "Little Tunes for the Piano" (original), 44 pages
        "Lullaby" (original), 24 pages
        "March" et al. (original), 120 pages
        "Misc. Sketches incl. Choral Work for 'Farewell'" (original), 79 pages
        "Notes for 'By Blue Ontario's Shore" (original), 24 pages
      - [Untitled] (Box 5)
        "Notes on 'By Blue Ontario's Shore"' (original), 55 pages
        "Of Love" et al. (original), 48 pages
        "Proverbs of Lao-Tsu" (original), 73 pages
        "Scraps" (original), 37 pages
        "Sketches of Overture and Piano Fugue Also College Song" (orig.), 51 pages
        "Songs" (original), 70 pages
        "Songs '50" (original), 46 pages
        "String Quartet in A Minor Incl. 4 Movements" (original), 31 pages
        "Table of Simple Newms and Song" (original), 53 pages
        "Tempest Notes" (original), 15 pages
        "Tunes for Drumlin Garden" (original & typescript), 78 pages
    - Sketches, miscellaneous
      - "The Bat" (Oversize 10)
        "The Bat" et al. (original), 190 pages
      - "Love" (Oversize 10)
        "Love" et al. (original and reproduction), 108 pages
      - "Passacaglia", 2 folders (Oversize 10)
        "Passacaglia" et al. (original), 300 pages
    - Songs, bound
      - American Songs Taken from Life, 1 volume (Oversize 11)
        Contents:
        "Sourwood Mountain" lyrics (printed), 1 page
        "Sourwood Mountain" (original), 1 page
        "Come All Ye Fair" (reproduction) (original?), 3 pages
        "Hammer Song" (reproduction) (original?), 2 pages
        "Common Bill" (original), 2 pages
        "In the Days of Old Rameses" lyrics (printed), 1 page
        "In the Days of Old Rameses" (original), 2 pages
        "Bird in a Cage" (original), 2 pages
        "What Kind o' Pants (reproduction), 1 page
        "Way Over" (reproduction), 1 page
        "Red Iron Ore" (rep., 1 page
        "My Lulu" (reproduction), 2 pages
        "Casey Jones" (original), 7 pages
        "Fond Affection" (original), 2 pages
        "Wizard Oil" lyrics (printed), 1 page
        "Wizard Oil" (original), 1 pages
        "Don' Let Yo Watch Run Down" (original), pages
        "Yes, I Do" (original), 2 pages
        "Walky-Talky Jenny" (original), 2 pages
        "Walky-Talky Jenny" lyrics (printed), 1 page
        "El-a-noy" (original), 2 pages
        "Times Gettin Hard" (reproduction), 1 pages
        "The Hearse Song" (reproduction), 1 pages
        "Irish Lullaby" (reproduction), 1 pages
        "Walk In" (reproduction), 1 pages
        "St. James Hospital" (reproduction), 2 pages
        "Days of Forty-nine" (reproduction), 2 pages
        "The Cruel Ship's Carpenter" (reproduction), 3 pages
        "Putman's Hill" (reproduction), 1 pages
        "Hick's Farewell" (reproduction), 1 pages
        "Buffalo Gals" (reproduction), 2 pages
        "The Hypocrite and the Concubine" (reproduction), 2 pages
        "Trabbel On" (reproduction), 1 page
        "Lo Lotte" (reproduction), 1 page
      - Four Lyrics, 1 volume (Oversize 11)
        "Schilflied" German and English (original), 3 pages
        "Ich Liebe Dich" German and English (original), 2 pages
        "Ach Lieb, Ich Muss Nun Scheiden" German (original), 2 pages
      - Of a Feather: Songs to Verses by Marie Welsh, 1 volume (Oversize 11)
        "The Dove" (original), 2 pages
        "The Vulture" (original), 2 pages
        "The Pigeon" (original), 3 pages
        "The Condor" (original), 2 pages
        "The Sparrow" (original), 1 page
        "The Pigeon" (original), 2 pages
        "The Condor" (original), 1 page
        "The Vulture" (original), 1 page
      - Early Songs, 1 volume (Oversize 30)
        "Wandl'ich in dem Wald des Abends" (Heine) German (original), 4 pages
        "Wandl'ich in dem Wald des Abends" (Heine) German (original), 3 pages
        "Der Brief" (original) in German, 4 pages
        "Frielingsgrusz" (original) in German, 3 pages
        "Serse gieht duch mien gemlith" (Heine) German (original), 3 pages
        "Childe Harold" (Heine) (original) in German, 2 pages
        "Aus Meinen grossen Schmergen" (original) in German, 4 pages
        "Where Go the Boats?" (original) in English, 2 pages
        "Looking-Glass River" (original) in English, 3 pages
        "Schniezlied" (Heine) (original) in English, 4 pages
        "Mit einem gemalten Band" (original) in German, 4 pages
        "Es War ein Fauler Schieffen" (original) in German, 3 pages
      - Songs, 1 volume (Oversize 11)
        "Cape Cod" (original), 5 pages
        "May Day" (original), 2 pages
        "The River" (original), 3 pages
        "Epitaph" (reproduction), 1 page
        "Omaha" (reproduction), 4 pages
        "Fog" (original), 2 pages
        "Rather" (original), 1 page
        "Where Go the Boats?" (original), 2 pages
        "Some Little Artie Flower" (original), 2 pages
        "The Grass" (original), 3 pages
        "Vespers" (original), 1 page
        Practice Sheet (original), 1 page
        "Never To Know" (original), 2 pages
      - Songs, 1 volume (Oversize 11)
        "First Day" (original), 3 pages
        "Twilight" (original), 2 pages
        "Ancient Christmas Carol" (original), 3 pages/2 pages, 2 copies
        "My River Runs to Thee"(original), 2 pages
        "Let Down the Bars" (original), 2 pages
        "I'm Nobody" (original), 2 pages
        "Epitaph" (original), 2 pages
        "Ancient Christmas Carol" (original), 2 pages
        "Wanderers Night Song" (original), 2 pages
        "Der Soldat" (original), 2 pages
        "As If the Sea Should Not Part" (original), 1 page
        "Wild Nights" (original), 3 pages
        "It's Coming -- the Postponeless Creature" (original), 2 pages
        "My River Runs to Thee" (original), 2 pages
        "There Is a Solitude of Space" (original), 3 pages
        "I Felt a Funeral In My Brain" (original), 3 pages
        "She Went As Quiet as the Dew" (original), 2 pages
        "The Grass So Little Has to Do" (original), 4 pages
        "So Set Its Sun in Thee" (original)., 2 pages
        "The Heart Asks Pleasure First" (original), 1 page
        "Savior" (original), 3 pages
        "Epitaph" (original), 1 page
        "The Sobbing of the Bells" (original), 3 pages
        "The Last Invocation" (original), 2 pages
        "Beat! Beat! Drums!" (original),, 5 pages
        "Joy, Shipmate, Joy!" (original), 3 pages
        "One Thought Ever at the Fore" (original), 2 pages
        "Grand Is the Seen" (original), 5 pages
        "Whispers of Heavenly Death" (original), 3 pages
        "Darest Thou Now, O Soul" (original), 7 pages
        "Anthem For the United States" (original), 2 pages
        "Love, O Love" (original)', 2 pages
        "Drivin' Steel" (original), 2 pages
        "Brady" (original), 5 pages
        "The Colorado Trail" (original), 2 pages
        "Wastin' Time" (original), 3 pages
        "Great Gawd!" (original), 2 pages
        "Low Bridge or the Erie Canal" (original), 4 pages
        "De Boll Weevil" (original), 6 pages
        "Peepin' Through the Knothole" (original), 4 pages
        "Midnight Special" (original), 3 pages
        "Sucking Cider" (original), 2 pages
        "De Sunshine Special" (original), 2 pages
        "O, My Honey!" (original), 1 page
        "O Bury Me Not" (original), 3 pages
        "Anthem For the United States" (original), 1 page
        "Grandioso" (original), 1 page
      - Songs, 1 volume (Oversize 12)
        "Grand is the Seen" (printed), 3 pages
        "The Last Invocation" (printed), 2 pages
        "Darest Thou Now, O Soul?" (printed), 6 pages
        "Twilight" (printed), 2 pages
        "One Thought Ever At the Fore"(printed), 2 pages
        "Joy, Shipmate, Joys" (printed), 2 pages
        "Whispers of Heavenly Death" (printed), 4 pages
        "The Sobbing of the Bells" (printed), 3 pages
        Ten Songs by Ernst Bacon pub. by Ernst Bacon (printed), 35 pages
        "Du bist wie eine Blume" (Heine) (original) Translated on reverse side, 2 pages
        "Ich hab' Dich geliebt" (original), 2 pages
        "Ach Lieb, ich muss nun scheiden" (reproduction), 2 pages
        "Schubert" (reproduction), 2 pages
        "Dei Jedem Morgengrauen" (reproduction), 2 pages
        "Der Soldat" (reproduction), 2 pages
        "Sporuch" (reproduction), 1 page
        "Mit deinen blauen Augen" (Heine) (original), 2 pages
        "Vergiszmeinnicht" (original), 2 pages
        "An den Mond" (original), 6 pages, 1 page translated into English
      - Two Serious Poems, 1 volume (Oversize 11)
        "O Thou Who in Heaven Art" (reproduction) in German & English, 3 pages
        "Prayer" (original) in German ("Gebet") and English, 5 pages
    - Songs, unbound
      - Folio 1 (Oversize 11)
        "Come All Ye Fair" (original), 1 page
        "...Girl" (original) (p. 1, 2), 2 pages
        "A Carol" (original), 1 page
        "A Carol" (original), 2 pages
        "Preface" (original), 5 pages
        "Afterthought" (original), 2 pages
        3 Miscellaneous Sheets (original), 3 pages
        "Euclid" (original), 1 page
        "The White Window" (original), 1 page
        "A Newcomer Arrives in this World" (original), 2 pages
        "...Brady" (original), 2 pages
        Miscellaneous- Untitled (original), 8 pages
        "Duet VII" (original), 4 pages
        Miscellaneous Scores (original), 8 pages
        "The Deep Sea" (original), 2 pages
        "Anthem to the United States" (original), 1 page
        "XVIII Chorus" (original), 4 pages
        "XXVIIb Duet" (original), 2 pages
        "IV Dialogue" (original), 1 page
        "XVI Chorus" (original), 1 page
        "A Fairy" (original), 3 pages
        "Don't Let Old..." (original), 8 pages [missing, 2/8/2017]
        "XXV Song" (original), 7 pages
        "VII Recitation" (original), 2 pages
        "The Outang (Orang-Outang) and the Elephant" (lyrics, no score) (original), 1 page
        "XXIVb Recit." (original), 1 page
        "XXV Recit." (original), 1 page
        "XIV Song" (origlpal), 2 pages
        "II Song" (original), 2 pages
        "IV Dialogue" (original), 2 pages
      - Folio 2 (Oversize 12)
        "The Forsaken Heart" (original), 3 pages
        "De Boll Weevil" (original), 5 pages
        "Sourwood Mountain" (original), 2 pages
        "Stars" (original), 2 pages
        "To Musique, To Becalme His Fevers" (original), 3 pages
        "The Divine Ship" (original), 1 page, 2 copies
        "The Little Stone" (original), 2 pages
        "Of Love" (original), 1 page
        "My Lulu" (original), 3 pages
        D3 "The Commonplace" (original), 3 pages
        D2 "A Clear Midnight" (original), 2 pages
        "The Commonplace" (original), 2 pages
        "Adam and Eve" (original), 3 pages
        "Is There Such a Thing As Day?" (original), 2 pages
        "To Make a Prairie" (original), 2 pages
        "Sons of Snow-White Heads" (original), 3 pages
        "Velvet People" (original), 4 pages
        "To Musique To Becalme His Fever" (original), 2 pages
        "These Yellow Sands" (original), 2 pages
        "Gentle Greeting" (original), 2 pages
        "The Lamb" (original), 3 pages
        "Low Bridge or the Erie Canal" (original), 3 pages
        "Careless Love" (original), 2 pages
        "So Bashful When I Spied Her" (original), 2 pages
        "The Grass" (revised version) (original), 3 pages
        "Sinful Shoe" (original), 3 pages
        "Let Her Go Hang" (original), 2 pages
        "Come Slowly Eden" (original), 2 pages
        "Stephano's Song" (original), 1 page
        "Lullaby" (original), 4 pages
      - SIngle songs (Oversize 12)
        Piano score for "The River Queen" (original), 7 pages
- Manuscripts, literary
  - Address, Radio
    - "Radio Address by Ernst Bacon", Oct. 27, 1941; 6 pages (Box 5)
  - Articles
    - [Looseleaf binder, untitled], 2 folders (Box 6)
      "Musical Driftings" American Scholar, typewritten copy, 12 pages
      "Orchestras and Conductors" typewritten copy with holograph corrections, 8 pages
      "Music After the War" typewritten copy, 8 pages
      "The American Musical Credo" typewritten copy with holo. corrections, 5 pages
      "A New Policy for Symphony Conductors" typewritten copy, 7 pages
      "The Philharmonic Barshaw" typewritten copy (carbon), 11 pages
      Note, "one concerto unwritten...the concerto and orchestra" typewritten copy, 1 page
      "American Music and the Colleges" typewritten copy, 7 pages
      "The Land of Impractice" typescript, 52 pages
      "Who Writes Music?" typescript, 5 pages
      "The Teacher" typescript, 5 pages
      "The Clear Spring" typescript, 6 pages
      "Unpaved Roads" typescript with holograph corrections, 8 pages
      "The Assessor" typescript with correction, 5 pages
      "Of Schools and the Provinces" typescript, 8 pages
      "The Birth of Music" typescript with corrections, 8 pages
      "Musical Shop-Talk" typescript, 24 pages
      "Mr. President and the Faculty of Converse College" typescript, 7 pages
      "Proposal for the Music School" typescript, 9 pages
      "Outline of a New Orchestral Policy" typescript, 4 pages
      "The Metropolitan Opera in American Art" typescript, 12 pages
      "On the World's Greatest Bridge" typescript, 4 pages
  - Books
    - Notes on the Piano, incomplete typescript copy; 2 copies in 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Notes on the Piano, partial holograph and typescript copy (Box 6)
  - Dialogues
    - Imaginary Dialogues / Ernst Bacon, April 28, 1989; bound, blue covers (Box 7)
  - Plays
    - Take Your Choice / Ernst Bacon, Phil Maturas, Raisch Stol, typescript (Box 7)
- Published material
  - Articles
    - About Ernst Bacon
      - "Ernst Bacon," Musical America, April 1949; 2 pages (Box 7)
    - By Ernst Bacon
      - "An Academic Stepchild," Converse Literary Journal, 3 pages (Box 7)
      - "College, Town and Music," Bulletin of the Assn. of American Colleges, 3 pages (Box 7)
      - "The Converse College Music Center," Southern Literary Messenger, 1942; 5 pages (Box 7)
      - "Has the Native Culture a Future?" Musical Courier, 1 page (Box 7)
      - "Means and Extremes," The Provincial Musician, April 1937; 1 page (Box 7)
      - "Music and Intuition," Music Teachers National Assn. Bulletin, 1949; 4 pages (Box 7)
      - "Musical Driftings," The American Scholar (Phi Beta Kappa Quarterly), Spring 1941; 7 pages (Box 7)
      - "On Musical Study," Southwestern Musician, March 1949; 6 pages (Box 7)
      - "Poetry in Search of Music: The Songs of Ernst Bacon," Sewanee Review, 1941; 3 pages (Box 7)
      - "Technique versus Talent," The Provincial Musician, March 1937; 6 pages (Box 7)
      - "Toward a Musical Home Rule," The Southern Literary Messenger, April 1940; 6 pages (Box 7)
      - "Who Writes Music?" Opera House News, Nov. 1937; 2 pages (Box 7)
  - Booklets
    - "Our Musical Idiom," The Open Court Publishing Company, Chicago, 1917; 48 pages (Box 7)
  - Music scores
    - The Burr Frolic, Associated Music Publishers, 1944 (Box 7)
    - Ten Songs by Ernst Bacon, self-published, 35 pages (Oversize 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings
    - Berkeley Daily Gazette "Words on Music" column, 1965 (Box 5)
      "Time and the Avant-Garde,” Feb. 26, 1965
      "The Sad Exodus from Our Area,” April 2, 1965
      "The Doctoral Complot,” April 16, 1965
      "Degrees 'Livil' All Ranks,,” April 26, 1965
      "Secretary Bird in a Flap,” May 5, 1965
      "Confessions of a Critic,” May 12, 1965
      "The Symphony as a Civil Institution,” May 14, 1965
      "Lets Revive the Salon,” May 19, 1965
      "Farmers' Museum Fascinating Place"May 21, 1965
      "A Major Career in Bay Area,” May 26, 1965
      "Der Herr Dictator,” May 28, 1965
    - New York Times (Box 5)
      "Sees Music Aids in Small School," Dec. 24, 1939
      "Place of the American Interpreter," Jan. 2, 1944
- Additions: University Archives
  All material in this series transferred from University Archives, 1991, and remains largely in original order.
  Some of this material duplicates material in the preceding portion of the collection.
  - Compositions [transfer from University Archives]
    This material was transferred from University Archives, 1991.
    - From These States (Gathered Along Unpaved Roads): A Suite for Symphony Orchestra, N.Y., Associated Music Publishers, 1951; 1 volume (Oversize 13)
      Laying the Rails (a sledge hammer song)
      Source of the Tennessee
      The Sunless Pines
      The Saluda Barn Dance
      The Cliff Dwellers (no ancient cliffs, these)
      Wizard Oil
      Storm over Huron
      Lullaby to a Sick Child
      Polly's Murder
      Hickory Gap
      The Timberline Express
    - Quiet Airs, S.U. Press & Mercury Music Corp., 1952; 1 volume (Oversize 13)
      Twilight, To Douglas Moore